<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>#JulyOT Blog</title>
        <link>https://JulyOT.dev/blog</link>
        <description>#JulyOT Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[07: A Closed Captioning Example on RaspberryPi using Azure Cognitive services]]></title>
            <link>https://JulyOT.dev/blog/07-closed-captioning-rpi</link>
            <guid>07-closed-captioning-rpi</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Welcome to Day 7 of #JulyOT!!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Welcome to Day 7 of <strong>#JulyOT</strong>!!</p></blockquote><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Welcome banner" src="/assets/images/JulyOT-banner-7-closed-captioning-75ac3dc342a459b423a1cdb0faa6de88.png" width="1000" height="420" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><em>Build a close captioning tool using a Raspberry Pi and Azure</em></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-project">The project<a class="hash-link" href="#the-project" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Check out this cool GitHub repo that shows you how to use the Azure Cognitive services from Microsoft and build an example of the Speech to text on a IoT device like raspberry. We will be using youtube videos for our source of speech which would be the input, we will consume the speech data via Mic connected to raspberry and display the converted text in real time over a LCD screen.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="see-it-in-action">See it in action<a class="hash-link" href="#see-it-in-action" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>Check out this video to see this project in action.</p><video width="640" height="480" controls=""><source src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/46184494/172901241-2b21438e-2600-4397-a6b6-4cd5b5c7c63d.mp4" type="video/mp4"></video><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="get-the-instructions">Get the instructions<a class="hash-link" href="#get-the-instructions" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>Check out the <a href="https://github.com/m-mohsin-ali/closed-captioning-azure-speech-ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub repo</a> for all the instructions.</p><form action="https://github.com/m-mohsin-ali/closed-captioning-azure-speech-ai" target="_blank"><input type="submit" value="GitHub repo" class="clean-btn button button--primary margin-left--md"></form>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>30days</category>
            <category>iot</category>
            <category>iot4b</category>
            <category>aiatedge</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[07: Plug and Play IoT device development with PnPFlow]]></title>
            <link>https://JulyOT.dev/blog/07-pnpflow</link>
            <guid>07-pnpflow</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Welcome to Day 7 of #JulyOT!!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Welcome to Day 7 of <strong>#JulyOT</strong>!!</p></blockquote><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Welcome banner" src="/assets/images/JulyOT-banner-7-pnpflow-93894831756f4f4ad38b21093b787ae7.png" width="1000" height="420" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-we-have-for-you-today">What we have for you today<a class="hash-link" href="#what-we-have-for-you-today" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ul><li><a href="#plug-and-play-story-on-windows"><strong>Plug and Play on Windows</strong></a></li><li><a href="#azure-iot-plug-and-play"><strong>Azure IoT Plug and Play</strong></a></li><li><a href="#the-rise-of-low-code-iot-development"><strong>The rise of Low-code IoT development</strong></a></li><li><a href="#about-m5stack"><strong>About M5STACK</strong></a></li><li><a href="#what-is-pnpflow"><strong>What is PnPFlow?</strong></a></li><li><a href="#how-does-pnpflow-work"><strong>How does PnPFlow work</strong></a></li><li><a href="#associated-links"><strong>Associated links</strong></a></li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="watch-the-introduction-to-pnpflow">Watch the introduction to PnPFlow<a class="hash-link" href="#watch-the-introduction-to-pnpflow" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Oo8HVQYg_ok" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"></iframe><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="plug-and-play-on-windows">Plug and Play on Windows<a class="hash-link" href="#plug-and-play-on-windows" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Everyone loves plug-and-play. When you connect a printer or a disk to your computer, they just work, and you don't have to worry about having installing drivers or configuring devices.</p><p>The introduction of the <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/windows-hardware/drivers/kernel/introduction-to-plug-and-play?wt.mc_id=eventspg_16482_webpage_reactor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Windows Plug and Play</a> framework solved problems with installing and configuring devices. The Plug and Play framework provided a standard interface for device builders, driver developers and the operating system.</p><p>Windows Plug and Play provides a set of rules for device discovery, driver interfaces, device configuration, and user notification. When everyone communicates according to unified rules, plug-and-play become a reality, end users can use devices without worrying how to set them up.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="IOT plug and play banner" src="/assets/images/iotpnp-530379d5730083856bada8b57e72e1dc.png" width="1434" height="447" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="iot-plug-and-play">IoT Plug and Play<a class="hash-link" href="#iot-plug-and-play" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>From the PC industry to the IoT world, the situation is even more complicated. Fragmentation in the IoT industry is a long-standing problem. There are many players involved, and there aren't well-accepted standards for interoperability. Complexity increases costs and slows down the progress of enterprise IoT deployment and digital transformation.</p><p><a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/azure/iot-develop/overview-iot-plug-and-play?wt.mc_id=eventspg_16482_webpage_reactor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IoT Plug and Play</a> is Microsoft's answer to IoT interoperability. Building an ecosystem to provide seamless integration between off-the-shelf devices and cloud solutions.</p><p>IoT Plug and Play is based on the open modeling language <a href="https://github.com/Azure/opendigitaltwins-dtdl/blob/master/DTDL/v2/dtdlv2.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">DTDL</a> that allows IoT devices to declare their capabilities to a solution. At the center of IoT Plug and Play is a schema that describes device capabilities with a <a href="https://json-ld.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">JSON-LD</a> model document.</p><p>An IoT Plug and Play model uses the following interfaces to describe and model any device:</p><ul><li>Telemetry
Usually time-series data like temperature measurements or events such as alerts).</li><li>Properties
Attributes like firmware version or long-running settings like target fan speed.</li><li>Commands
For example, reboot a device, or open a door lock.</li></ul><p>The modeling architecture supports interface reuse across device capability models to facilitate collaboration and speed development.</p><p>Solutions built on Azure IoT, including Azure IoT Hub and Central, support IoT Plug and Play natively. Application developers can also build IoT Plug and Play enabled solutions that adapt to IoT devices by parsing their DTDL models.</p><blockquote><p>IoT Plug and Play is also part of the <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/azure/partners/azure-certified-device?wt.mc_id=eventspg_16482_webpage_reactor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure Certified Device program</a> which enables device developers to differentiate and certify their IoT devices and a central catalogue for customers to discover IoT devices.</p></blockquote><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-rise-of-low-code-iot-development">The rise of Low-code IoT development<a class="hash-link" href="#the-rise-of-low-code-iot-development" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>The benefits of plug-and-play go beyond just connecting two systems, it is also useful for accelerating IoT hardware and software development.</p><p>To achieve hardware plug-and-play, the interface should be standardized and the hardware should be modular. Just like Lego building blocks, various prototypes can be easily designed. From the rise of Arduino to various open-source hardware, such as Microsoft <a href="https://microsoft.github.io/jacdac-docs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jacdac</a>, device manufacturers want ways to make hardware connections less expensive and more convenient.</p><p>From a software development perspective, graphical programming and low-code development are very popular. <a href="https://nodered.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">NodeRed</a> and Microsoft <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/makecode?wt.mc_id=eventspg_16482_webpage_reactor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MakeCode</a> are two great examples. Anyone can quickly implement business logic and build prototypes without requiring deep professional knowledge and programming skills. Countless innovative projects around the world use these platforms to solve real problems.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="introducing-m5stack">Introducing M5STACK<a class="hash-link" href="#introducing-m5stack" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>M5STACK is a great example of a company that builds products that are both modular and use low-code graphic programming, this makes IoT development easier.</p><p><a href="https://m5stack.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">M5STACK</a>, based in Shenzhen, China, is a technology company that designs and manufactures open-source IoT development devices for the global market. They're also an IoT device partner of Microsoft Azure, offering IoT modules and engineering services to enterprise customers.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="A photo of a huge range of M5 stack devices such as sensors and actuators" src="/assets/images/m5stackdevice-442d9fe59aa28b564fcb0a3b82dfab21.png" width="1013" height="647" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>M5STACK builds hundreds of sensors, actuators, and communication modules that can be connected through standard interfaces. These modules plug and play with the <a href="https://flow.m5stack.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">UIFLOW</a> low-code graphical programming IDE to give the best IoT project prototyping experience from entry-level hobbyists to professional developers.</p><p>With UIFLOW, a user builds a solution with single blocks, or they can implement more advanced scenarios by combining several blocks. For example, blocks can be combined to move data between industrial networks like Modbus to internet services over TCP/IP without requiring a deep understanding of these protocols.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="A block based editor for coding the M5 stack" src="/assets/images/uiflow-a26de8355a3ba969db44566a7d2700fa.png" width="1895" height="795" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>M5STACK aims to cooperate with other companies to create a more open and interconnected IoT developer platform. Their <a href="https://devicecatalog.azure.com/devices/84fe4cc3-cdf1-48a1-8b58-07685890f359" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">kits</a> are certified for Azure IoT Plug and Play. UIFLOW has advanced <a href="https://docs.m5stack.com/en/uiflow/iotcloud/azure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure IoT support</a> built-in.  Users can build a device with just a few clicks to connect to Azure IoT Hub or Azure IoT Central.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-is-pnpflow">What is PnPFlow?<a class="hash-link" href="#what-is-pnpflow" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Project PnPFlow is the latest collaboration between M5STACK and the Azure IoT team. A better together experience for developer to build an IoT Plug and Play device without knowing the complexity of Plug and Play protocol and DTDL model. All you have to do is to drag and drop blocks to build a business-centric application in UIFLOW. The device will be automatically provisioned on Azure IoT Central and seamlessly will work with IoT Central template based web-UI .</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="how-does-pnpflow-work">How does PnPFlow work?<a class="hash-link" href="#how-does-pnpflow-work" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ol><li><p>Each supported hardware component, be it standalone hardware like a UNIT sensor, or a built-in Core module component, such as a built-in RTC peripheral, have capabilities modeled as an IoT Plug and Play interface. The models are hosted on <a href="https://github.com/m5stack/M5-iot-plugandplay-models" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Github</a>.</p></li><li><p>The UIFLOW has built-in intelligence to load predefined models, generate 'Smart' blocks to represent each telemetry, property, or command operation, and associate with hardware blocks using an assignment expression. The l-value is a schema-aware object defined in the model, and the r-value is the corresponding hardware operations or a user-provided value.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="A block based editor showing how to write PnP flow code" src="/assets/images/pnpflowblock-740c2a1c5de0717e546ce33e9e645146.png" width="1198" height="643" class="img_ev3q"></p></li><li><p>The user can choose one or more 'Smart' blocks, manipulate them and integrate them with custom application logic. The UIFLOW will dynamically compose predefined interfaces into a single top-level device model.</p></li><li><p>To further improve developer experience, UIFLOW  natively integrates with Azure IoT Central. Users can log in to their IoT Central applications, create and update device templates, and manage device identities without leaving UIFLOW. The IoT Central application template will be customized to reflect the device's capabilities and a default page will be automatically generated.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="An animated GIF showing how to connect the UI flow block based editor to Azure IoT Central" src="/assets/images/pnpflow-iotcentral-1ce337b80cf94a488e9166af9a51946c.gif" width="1916" height="975" class="img_ev3q"></p></li></ol><p>Are you exciting about Plug and Play IoT development? Get some devices from M5STACK and go to <a href="https://flow.m5stack.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">UIFLOW</a> to test it out.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="associated-links">Associated links<a class="hash-link" href="#associated-links" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ul><li><a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/build-with-azure-iot-central-and-iot-plug-and-play/?wt.mc_id=eventspg_16482_webpage_reactor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Build with Azure IoT Central and IoT Plug and Play</a></li><li><a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/azure/iot-develop/concepts-modeling-guide?wt.mc_id=eventspg_16482_webpage_reactor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Understanding IoT Plug and Play modeling</a></li><li><a href="https://docs.m5stack.com/en/quick_start/m5core/uiflow" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">M5STACK UIFLOW Documentation</a></li></ul>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>30days</category>
            <category>iot</category>
            <category>pnp</category>
            <category>low-code</category>
            <category>embeddediot</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[06: Edge Impulse Project of the Month competition]]></title>
            <link>https://JulyOT.dev/blog/06-edge-impulse-competition</link>
            <guid>06-edge-impulse-competition</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Welcome to Day 6 of #JulyOT!!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Welcome to Day 6 of <strong>#JulyOT</strong>!!</p></blockquote><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Post banner" src="/assets/images/JulyOT-banner-6-edge-impulse-competition-803c3b923665bcfba0ab6017eb16bcfd.png" width="1000" height="420" class="img_ev3q"></p><h1>Edge Impulse challenge of the month - July</h1><p><a href="https://edgeimpulse.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Edge Impulse</a> have announced their challenge of the month for July, perfecting timing for #JulyOT.</p><img src="/img/svg/edge-impulse-dark.svg" alt="Docusaurus themed image" class="themedImage_ToTc themedImage--light_HNdA"><img src="/img/svg/edge-impulse-light.svg" alt="Docusaurus themed image" class="themedImage_ToTc themedImage--dark_i4oU"><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="build-and-share-your-object-detection-project-in-minutes">Build and share your object detection project in minutes<a class="hash-link" href="#build-and-share-your-object-detection-project-in-minutes" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Public Projects help the community learn from each other, and teach developers and engineers how to solve real-world problems with Edge Impulse. This month we are asking developers to see what problems they can solve with object detection on tiny devices!</p><p>With object detection you are able to detect the presence and the position of any object within an image. Use our object detection pre-built ML block that leverages transfer learning to quickly get your device to detect the objects of your choice.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="win-prizes">Win prizes!<a class="hash-link" href="#win-prizes" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>The top prize for the best project is $2000 and an entry into their annual competition to win a macBook Pro, AirPods and an Edge Impulse backpack. 2 runners up get $200.</p><p>You can find all the details and the rules on the <a href="https://edgeimpulse.com/projectofthemonth" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Edge Impulse competition page</a>.</p><form action="https://edgeimpulse.com/projectofthemonth" target="_blank"><input type="submit" value="Learn more and enter" class="clean-btn button button--primary margin-left--md"></form>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>30days</category>
            <category>iot</category>
            <category>aiatedge</category>
            <category>embedded</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[05: Altair Everywhere]]></title>
            <link>https://JulyOT.dev/blog/julyot-day5-embedded</link>
            <guid>julyot-day5-embedded</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Welcome to Day 5 of #JulyOT!!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Welcome to Day 5 of <strong>#JulyOT</strong>!!</p></blockquote><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Post banner" src="/assets/images/JulyOT-banner-5-altair-a33c8f3bd41ae6352f1a5a335e05be9f.png" width="1000" height="420" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><em>The goal of the cloud-connected Altair project is to provide a unique blend of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Retrocomputing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">computing history</a> with modern cloud computing. You'll learn about computing fundamentals, software development, and modern IoT, Data, and AI cloud services that address today's real-world IT challenges.</em></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="run-altair-everywhere">Run Altair Everywhere<a class="hash-link" href="#run-altair-everywhere" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>The Altair Everywhere project is tested and runs on the following platforms:</p><ol><li><p>On a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/POSIX" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">POSIX</a> compatible operating system including Linux, Windows with <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/windows/wsl/install?wt.mc_id=eventspg_16482_webpage_reactor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">WSL 2</a>, macOS on Apple Silicon and Intel.</p></li><li><p><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Raspberry Pi</a>, models, Zero 1 &amp; 2, 2B, 3B, 3B, and 4 running Raspberry Pi OS.</p><table><thead><tr><th>Raspberry Pi with Pi Sense HAT</th><th>Raspberry Pi Sense HAT</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><img loading="lazy" alt="The image shows the address and data bus LEDs" src="/assets/images/raspberry_pi_sense_hat_map-219521f7247903276cd59d090845b3ea.png" width="562" height="379" class="img_ev3q"></td><td><img loading="lazy" alt="The gif shows the address and data bus LEDs in action" src="/assets/images/raspberry_pi_sense_hat-079bdc455c3a3502d2aaa72a6f7b69ed.gif" width="469" height="400" class="img_ev3q"></td></tr></tbody></table></li><li><p><a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/services/azure-sphere/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure Sphere Avnet and Seeed Developer Kits</a> running embedded Linux.</p><table><thead><tr><th>Azure Sphere with the Altair front panel kit</th><th>MikroE Retro Click</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><img loading="lazy" alt="The gif shows the Altair on Azure Sphere with the Altair front panel" src="/assets/images/altair_on_sphere-98abeed24d5bc60e757abebf5915ef90.gif" width="979" height="400" class="img_ev3q"></td><td><img loading="lazy" alt="The gif shows the address and data bus LEDs in action" src="/assets/images/avnet_retro_click-7b1a51a16e5d323ac421778d433c78d0.gif" width="332" height="400" class="img_ev3q"></td></tr></tbody></table></li></ol><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-well-cover">What We'll Cover<a class="hash-link" href="#what-well-cover" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>The Altair project can be viewed through three lenses:</p><ol><li>Learn how to develop multithreaded event-driven IoT C applications that scale from embedded <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microcontroller" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">microcontrollers</a> to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raspberry_Pi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Raspberry Pis</a>, to desktop-class computers.</li><li>A fantastic safe way to explore Intel 8080 machine-level programming and Assembly programming, along with C and BASIC development.</li><li>If you are interested in retro gaming, chill out playing retro games from yesteryear.</li></ol><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="cloud-services-integration">Cloud services integration<a class="hash-link" href="#cloud-services-integration" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Optionally, the project integrates free weather and pollution cloud services from Open Weather Map, Azure IoT Central, and Azure Anomaly Detection Cognitive Service. The following reports were generated from data published by the Altair emulator using data sourced from Open Weather Map.</p><table><thead><tr><th>IoT Central Sydney pollution report</th><th>Azure Anomaly Detection report</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><img loading="lazy" alt="The images shows pollution report for Sydney" src="/assets/images/iot_central_pollution_report-ac41244851068dc6e9880987e78e9d1a.png" width="600" height="400" class="img_ev3q"></td><td><img loading="lazy" alt="The following images shows temperature based anomalies" src="/assets/images/univariate-anomalies-ca2e171d017ac8c6f26ad82d99afd7b8.png" width="533" height="400" class="img_ev3q"></td></tr></tbody></table><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="get-started">Get Started<a class="hash-link" href="#get-started" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Head to the <a href="https://github.com/gloveboxes/Altair8800.Emulator.UN-X/wiki" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Altair Everywhere</a> repo, get started, have some fun, learn new skills, and impress your friends and family :)</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="altair-history">Altair History<a class="hash-link" href="#altair-history" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p><img loading="lazy" alt="The image shows the Altair 8800" src="/assets/images/altair-8800-smithsonian-museum-efa63f9b538227319fa6d4ec8ca701b7.png" width="1200" height="600" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Altair_8800,_Smithsonian_Museum.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Altair 8800 image attribution - Smithsonian Museum</a></p><p>The Altair 8800 was built on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intel_8080?azure-portal=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Intel 8080</a> CPU, the second 8-bit microprocessor manufactured by Intel in 1974. By today's standards, it's a simple CPU design, perfect for learning computing fundamentals because of its small instruction set.</p><p>The original Altair 8800 was programmed by setting switches on the front panel. It was a painstaking, error-prone process to load and run a program. The Altair 8800 had a series of LEDs and switches that you used to load apps and determine the state of the Altair.</p><p>You could save and load applications from a paper tape reader connected to the Altair 8800. As the Altair 8800 grew in popularity, more options became available. You could attach a keyboard, a computer monitor, and disk drives, a more reliable way to save and load applications.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>30days</category>
            <category>iot</category>
            <category>iot4b</category>
            <category>embeddediot</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[04: Detect the very big with the very small – counting bears with TinyML meetup from IoT North]]></title>
            <link>https://JulyOT.dev/blog/julyot-day4</link>
            <guid>julyot-day4</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Welcome to Day 4 of #JulyOT!!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Welcome to Day 4 of <strong>#JulyOT</strong>!!</p></blockquote><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Page banner" src="/assets/images/JulyOT-banner-4-iot-north-165adf829cc81694d4fcdea9b9c94b91.png" width="1000" height="420" class="img_ev3q"></p><h1>Detect the very big with the very small – counting bears with TinyML meetup from IoT North</h1><p>Today we have a sneak peek at a meetup coming tomorrow (5th July), to give you time to sign up and join! This meetup event will be live streamed from IoT North, and starts on the 5th July at 6PM BST/10AM PDT.</p><p>Catch the recording here!</p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8imvkDhdxnw" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"></iframe><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="iot-north">IoT North<a class="hash-link" href="#iot-north" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>IoT North is meetup for makers and developers working on all kinds of hardware and software projects around the Internet of Things (IoT). Come and talk about your projects, what you're working on and share experiences.</p><p>Now a part of IoT North - <a href="http://www.IoTNorth.uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.IoTNorth.uk</a> - giving businesses a North in IoT</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-this-meetup-is-about">What this meetup is about<a class="hash-link" href="#what-this-meetup-is-about" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Jim left the UK a few years ago to move to the Pacific North West of the US. Back in the UK the scariest animal he might have encountered would be a sudden hedgehog, but in Washington State where he lives it seems there are bears! He even lost an apple tree and a fence to one once.</p><p>A useful tool for him would be a bear detector – a device to alert him if there are bears in the garden. Such a tool could be built using an AI model trained in the cloud and running on a powerful computer. But who wants to risk a powerful computer outside when there are bears?</p><p>What if he could run a bear detector on a relatively inexpensive microcontroller, then see the results on a cloud dashboard?</p><p>This is where TinyML comes in! TinyML is shrinking AI models down very small, as in kilobytes in size, then running them on low power microcontrollers, or tiny computers like a Raspberry Pi Zero.</p><p>In this session Jim will train a bear detector using <a href="https://edgeimpulse.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Edge Impulse</a>, an on-line development platform for TinyML models, taking advantage of their new FOMO object detection model. He’ll then show how to run this model on a low powered device, uploading the detection results to an Azure IoT Central dashboard.</p><p>By the end of this session, you will have an understanding of TinyML, how to train models, how to visualize data, and just how wary of bears Jim actually is…</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>30days</category>
            <category>iot</category>
            <category>aiatedge</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[02: IoT for beginners]]></title>
            <link>https://JulyOT.dev/blog/julyot-day2</link>
            <guid>julyot-day2</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Welcome to Day 2 of #JulyOT!!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Welcome to Day 2 of <strong>#JulyOT</strong>!! </p></blockquote><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Page banner" src="/assets/images/JulyOT-banner-2-iot-for-beginners-77c238a33207a9804e4228861b97de12.png" width="1000" height="420" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>As we go into the first weekend of July, and a long weekend for some, there's no better time to brush up on your basics.</p><p>For day 2 of #JulyOT we are dipping into the archives to bring you <a href="https://aka.ms/iot-beginners" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IoT for Beginners</a>, a 12-week, 24-lesson free and open source IoT curriculum to teach you IoT from the ground up. You can use this for self learning, or re-use hte contents any way you need for teaching or learning. Whether you are a professional developer who wants to learn a new skill, or a teacher looking for IoT classroom content, this curriculum is for you.</p><form action="https://aka.ms/iot-beginners" target="_blank"><input type="submit" value="Start the course" class="clean-btn button button--primary margin-left--md"></form><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="course-outline">Course outline<a class="hash-link" href="#course-outline" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://github.com/microsoft/IoT-For-Beginners/raw/main/sketchnotes/Roadmap.jpg" alt="A rodmap for IoT for beginners" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>IoT for Beginners is split into 6 projects, each one teaching important IoT concepts and coupled with you actually building something. The projects follow the path from farm to table, showing how IoT can improve the journey food makes, and covering industrial IoT, digital agriculture, AI on the edge, retail IoT, and consumer IoT.</p><ul><li>Introduction - build an IoT nightlight</li><li>Digital agriculture - build an automated watering system</li><li>Logistics - build a vehicle tracker with a dashboard and location alerts</li><li>Manufacturing - use AI on the edge to build a fruit monitor</li><li>Retail - use AI on the edge to do stock monitoring</li><li>Consumer - build a voice controlled smart timer</li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="meet-the-team">Meet the team<a class="hash-link" href="#meet-the-team" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>This course was put together as a collaboration between IoT experts at Microsoft, and students from all around the world. You can learn more from the following video:</p><p><a href="https://youtu.be/-wippUJRi5k" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" src="https://github.com/microsoft/IoT-For-Beginners/raw/main/images/IOT.gif" alt="Promo video" class="img_ev3q"></a></p><p><strong>Gif by</strong> <a href="https://linkedin.com/in/mohitjaisal" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mohit Jaisal</a></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="get-started">Get started<a class="hash-link" href="#get-started" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>What are you waiting for? Head to the <a href="https://aka.ms/iot-beginners" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IoT for Beginners repo on GitHub</a> and get started!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>30days</category>
            <category>iot</category>
            <category>iot4b</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[01: Getting started with nanoFramework!]]></title>
            <link>https://JulyOT.dev/blog/01-nano-framework</link>
            <guid>01-nano-framework</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Welcome to Day 1 of #JulyOT!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Welcome to Day 1 of <strong>#JulyOT</strong>!</p></blockquote><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Page banner" src="/assets/images/JulyOT-banner-1-nanoframework-fb5bd9ec0e79be338df59df895433a5c.png" width="1000" height="420" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-we-have-for-you-today">What we have for you today<a class="hash-link" href="#what-we-have-for-you-today" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ul><li><a href="#getting-started-with-nanoframework"><strong>Getting started with nanoFramework</strong></a></li><li><a href="#what-is-net-nanoframework"><strong>What is .NET nanoFramework?</strong></a></li><li><a href="#why-use-net-nanoframework"><strong>Why use .NET nanoFramework?</strong></a></li><li><a href="#associated-links"><strong>Associated links:</strong></a></li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="getting-started-with-nanoframework">Getting started with nanoFramework<a class="hash-link" href="#getting-started-with-nanoframework" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>.NET nanoFramework: Our mantra is about <strong>making it easy to write C# code for embedded systems!</strong> And all that we're doing here is about that. This free and Open Source platform enables the writing of managed code applications for constrained embedded devices. As a developer, you can use your powerful and familiar tools like Microsoft Visual Studio IDE and your .NET C# skills to write code on a microcontroller.</p><p>.NET nanoFramework supports a large variety of Micro Controller Units (MCU): STM32, ESP32, TI, and NXP. The .NET nanoFramework provides access to low-level IO and protocols, as well as networking and advanced security features allowing connection to the Cloud.</p><p>Here you'll find all the tools, examples, documentation and a great developer ecosystem to help you on your next embedded systems project.</p><blockquote><p><strong>New</strong>: Adoption of .NET nanoFramework is growing fast. It just reached 2 million NuGet downloads, it took 5 years to reach the first million and only 9 months for the second one! Read more about it <a href="https://www.nanoframework.net/2-million-nuget-downloads-and-counting/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a></p></blockquote><p>To get started, you can use our <a href="https://docs.nanoframework.net/content/getting-started-guides/getting-started-managed.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">step by step guide</a> containing as well short videos.</p><p>You'll go through the installation of the Visual Studio extension:</p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://docs.nanoframework.net/images/getting-started-guides/getting-started-extension-installation.gif" alt="step by step" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Then installing <code>nanoff</code>, the tool to flash your device, and flashing your device:</p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://docs.nanoframework.net/images/getting-started-guides/getting-started-install-nanoff-flash-esp32.gif" alt="install and flash nanoff" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>And then coding your first hello .NET nanoFramework application and setting debug breakpoints in your code:</p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://docs.nanoframework.net/images/getting-started-guides/getting-started-first-project.gif" alt="Hello nano" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>In a matter of a few minutes, you'll be up and running with .NET nanoFramework!</p><p>And a lot of samples to start: <a href="https://github.com/nanoframework/Samples" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/nanoframework/Samples</a></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-is-net-nanoframework">What is .NET nanoFramework?<a class="hash-link" href="#what-is-net-nanoframework" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>.NET <strong>nanoFramework</strong> is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_and_open-source_software" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">free and open-source</a> platform that enables the writing of managed code applications for constrained <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Embedded_system" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">embedded devices</a>. It is suitable for many types of projects including IoT sensors, wearables, academic proof of concept, robotics, hobbyist/makers creations, or even complex industrial equipment. The .NET nanoFramework makes development easier, faster, and less costly by giving embedded developers access to modern technologies and tools used by desktop application developers.</p><p>Developers can harness the powerful and familiar <a href="https://www.visualstudio.com/vs/?wt.mc_id=eventspg_16482_webpage_reactor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Microsoft Visual Studio IDE</a> and their <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/.NET_Framework" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">.NET</a> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/C_Sharp_(programming_language)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">C#</a> knowledge to quickly write code without having to worry about the low-level hardware intricacies of a microcontroller. Desktop .NET developers will feel “at home” and can use their skills in embedded systems development, enlarging the pool of qualified embedded developers. Using Microsoft Visual Studio, a developer can deploy and debug the code directly on real hardware.</p><p>The .NET nanoFramework includes a reduced version of the .NET <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Common_Language_Runtime" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Common Language Runtime</a> (CLR) and features a subset of the .NET base class libraries along with the most common APIs included in <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/uwp/api/?wt.mc_id=eventspg_16482_webpage_reactor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">.NET IoT</a> allowing code reuse from .NET IoT applications, thousands of code examples, and open source projects.</p><p>The project is supported by the .NET Foundation.</p><p>You can watch this video from the Microsoft <a href="https://aka.ms/iotshow" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IoT Show</a> featuring .NET nanoFramework connected to Azure IoT Hub, measuring a <a href="https://docs.nanoframework.net/devices/Iot.Device.Bmxx80.Bmp280.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">BMP280 sensors</a>, and using the unique deep sleep feature from microcontrollers. A real-life example with .NET nanoFramework:</p><p><a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/shows/internet-of-things-show/introduction-to-net-nanoframework?wt.mc_id=eventspg_16482_webpage_reactor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" alt="IoT Show" src="/assets/images/nanoframework-iot-show-bdea819a9957f31f152f8133e9a998da.jpg" width="480" height="360" class="img_ev3q"></a></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="why-use-net-nanoframework">Why use .NET nanoFramework?<a class="hash-link" href="#why-use-net-nanoframework" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>.NET <strong>nanoFramework</strong> is the perfect enabler for developing software that works on embedded devices. Start with a low-cost and readily available development board, then use nanoFramework to write, debug and deploy your code.</p><p>Whether this is your first foray into programming or you are a seasoned developer, if you want a powerful and easy-to-use tool for developing software that runs on embedded devices, you are in the right place. With its modular architecture, it's easy to grab the core components (like the CLR, debugger, and interpreter) and extend them to new hardware platforms, .NET nanoFramework is the perfect partner for your project. The current reference implementation uses <a href="http://www.chibios.org/dokuwiki/doku.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ChibiOS</a> supporting several <a href="http://www.st.com/content/st_com/en.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ST Microelectronics</a> development boards, Espressif <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ESP32" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ESP32</a>, Texas Instruments <a href="https://www.ti.com/tool/CC3220SF-LAUNCHXL" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CC3220 Launchpad</a>, <a href="https://www.ti.com/tool/LAUNCHXL-CC1352R1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CC1352 Launchpad</a>, and NXP <a href="https://www.nxp.com/part/MIMXRT1060-EVK#/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MIMXRT1060-EVK</a>.</p><p>Because it's completely <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_and_open-source_software" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">free and Open Source</a> you have access to and the ability to modify all parts of the code including the ability to leverage what others have already contributed. If you are willing to, you can help shape the future by contributing back to the project and rapidly growing community.</p><p>Here are a couple of supported boards:</p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://docs.nanoframework.net/images/reference-targets/nucleo64-f091rc.jpg" alt="nucleo" class="img_ev3q"><img loading="lazy" src="https://docs.nanoframework.net/images/reference-targets/esp32-devkitc.jpg" alt="esp32" class="img_ev3q"><img loading="lazy" src="https://docs.nanoframework.net/images/reference-targets/m5stack.jpg" alt="M5Stack" class="img_ev3q"><img loading="lazy" src="https://docs.nanoframework.net/images/reference-targets/orgpal-palthree.jpg" alt="OrgPall PalThree" class="img_ev3q"><img loading="lazy" src="https://docs.nanoframework.net/images/reference-targets/mimxrt1060_evk.jpg" alt="NXP" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Our reference boards can be found <a href="https://github.com/nanoframework/nf-interpreter#net-nanoframework-interpreter-for-reference-boards" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>. And community boards <a href="https://github.com/nanoframework/nf-Community-Targets#available-community-boards" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>. Depending on your board, it can be a matter of a few hours to get your board supported! A blog post will explain how.</p><p>Here are some of its unique features:</p><ul><li>Can run on resource-constrained devices with as low as 128kB of flash and 64kB of RAM.</li><li>Runs directly on bare metal. Currently, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ARM_Cortex-M" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ARM Cortex-M</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ESP32" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ESP32</a> devices are supported.</li><li>Supports common embedded peripherals and interconnects like GPIO, UART, SPI, I2C, USB, and networking.</li><li>Provides multi-threading support natively.</li><li>Support for energy-efficient operations such as devices running on batteries.</li><li>Support for Interop code allows developers to easily write libraries that have both managed (C#) and native code (C/C++).</li><li>No manual memory management because of its simpler mark-and-sweep <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Garbage_collection_(computer_science)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">garbage collector</a>.</li><li>Execution constraints to catch device lockups and crashes.</li></ul><p>Here are some advantages over other similar systems:</p><ul><li>First-class debugger experience right on the target hardware with breakpoints, single step, step into, step out, step over, pause and stop.</li><li>Powerful and free developer tools with <a href="https://www.visualstudio.com/vs/?wt.mc_id=eventspg_16482_webpage_reactor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Microsoft Visual Studio IDE</a>.</li><li>Support for a large range of inexpensive boards from several manufacturers including Discovery and Nucleo boards from <a href="http://www.st.com/content/st_com/en.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ST Microelectronics</a>, <a href="https://www.mikroe.com/quail" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Quail</a> from Mikrobus, <a href="https://www.wildernesslabs.co/Netduino" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Netduino</a> from Wilderness Labs, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ESP32" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ESP32</a> DevKit C, Texas Instruments <a href="https://www.ti.com/tool/CC3220SF-LAUNCHXL" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CC3220 Launchpad</a>, <a href="https://www.ti.com/tool/LAUNCHXL-CC1352R1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CC1352 Launchpad</a>, and NXP <a href="https://www.nxp.com/part/MIMXRT1060-EVK#/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MIMXRT1060-EVK</a>.</li><li>Easily expandable to other hardware and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Real-time_operating_system" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">RTOS</a> platforms. Currently targets <a href="https://developer.arm.com/embedded/cmsis" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CMSIS</a> and ESP32 FreeRTOS ports.</li><li>Completely free and Open Source. From the core components to the utilities used for building, deploying, debugging, and IDE components.</li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="associated-links">Associated links:<a class="hash-link" href="#associated-links" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ul><li>Official .NET nanoFramework <a href="https://www.nanoframework.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">site and blog</a>.</li><li><a href="https://docs.nanoframework.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">All our documentation</a> for API, classes, how to install, build your own images, architecture, and more!.</li><li>THE place to go to get any code: our <a href="https://github.com/nanoframework" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Github .NET nanoFramework</a>.</li></ul><p>Find us on Fridays all July! See you for another post on how to use GPIO, SPI, I2C, PWM, and more on .NET nanoFramework! And feedback is welcome.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>30days</category>
            <category>iot</category>
            <category>embeddediot</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[01: Welcome to #JulyOT!]]></title>
            <link>https://JulyOT.dev/blog/01-julyot-kickoff</link>
            <guid>01-julyot-kickoff</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Welcome to Day 1 of #JulyOT!!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Welcome to Day 1 of <strong>#JulyOT</strong>!!</p></blockquote><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Welcome banner" src="/assets/images/JulyOT-banner-1-welcome-62a0080c482ed6ee0b4f9233bffc4aa6.png" width="1000" height="420" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>#JulyOT 2022 is finally here, and we are excited to share 31 days of IoT goodness throughout this month.</p><p>Each weekday we will be publishing one or more articles here all grouped into the following themes:</p><ul><li>Beginners, makers, and students</li><li>Embedded development</li><li>AI on the Edge</li><li>Learning and certifications</li></ul><p>Some will be full blog posts, others will direct you to videos, GitHub repos, other blogs, or code samples.</p><p>Check back here every day for more IoT goodness.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="in-this-post">In this post<a class="hash-link" href="#in-this-post" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ul><li><a href="#iot-cloud-skills-challenge"><strong>Upskill by joining the IoT Cloud skills challenge</strong></a></li><li><a href="#iot-for-beginners"><strong>Learn IoT with IoT For Beginners</strong></a></li><li><a href="#digital-swag"><strong>Digital swag</strong></a></li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="iot-cloud-skills-challenge">IoT Cloud Skills Challenge<a class="hash-link" href="#iot-cloud-skills-challenge" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Want to become a subject matter in the IoT Domain? Take the <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/learn/challenges?id=261fd583-fa7b-4b1f-86eb-6a52b5468a23&amp;wt.mc_id=eventspg_16482_webpage_reactor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Microsoft Cloud Skills Challenge</a> - skill yourself up in 31 days and complete the Cloud Skills Challenge. This starts 1st July, so sign up now.</p><table><tbody><tr style="border:0px;background-color:#00000000"><td style="border:0px;text-align:center"></td><td style="border:0px;text-align:center"><form action="https://docs.microsoft.com/learn/challenges" target="_blank"><input type="submit" value="Join the Cloud Skills Challenge" class="clean-btn button button--primary margin-left--md"><input type="hidden" name="id" value="261fd583-fa7b-4b1f-86eb-6a52b5468a23"><input type="hidden" name="wt.mc_id" value="eventspg_16482_webpage_reactor"></form></td><td style="border:0px;text-align:center"></td></tr><tr style="border:0px;background-color:#00000000"><td style="border:0px;text-align:center"><img loading="lazy" src="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/media/learn/challenge/how_it_works_1.png?branch=main" width="75%" alt="A cuddly document and a purple yeti coding" class="img_ev3q"></td><td style="border:0px;text-align:center"><img loading="lazy" src="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/media/learn/challenge/how_it_works_2.png?branch=main" width="75%" alt="A cuddly document and a purple yeti coding" class="img_ev3q"></td><td style="border:0px;text-align:center"><img loading="lazy" src="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/media/learn/challenge/how_it_works_3.png?branch=main" width="75%" alt="A cuddly document and a purple yeti coding" class="img_ev3q"></td></tr><tr style="border:0px;background-color:#00000000"><td style="border:0px;vertical-align:top"><b>Compete</b><br><br>Benchmark your progress against friends and coworkers. It's always better when we learn together.</td><td style="border:0px;vertical-align:top"><b>Learn</b><br><br>Increase your understanding with easy-to-read instruction and stay up on the bleeding-edge of technology.</td><td style="border:0px;vertical-align:top"><b>Develop skills</b><br><br>By the end of the challenge, you will have marketable skills to better yourself and your career.</td></tr></tbody></table><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="iot-for-beginners">IoT For Beginners<a class="hash-link" href="#iot-for-beginners" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p><a href="https://aka.ms/iot-beginners" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IoT for beginners</a> is a free, open source, 24-lesson IoT curriculum. The first lesson is live-streamed today from the Microsoft Reactor. Catch the recording on the Microsoft Reactor YouTube channel.</p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1KVrBjSqS5s" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"></iframe><p>Learn more about IoT for Beginners on the official <a href="https://aka.ms/iot-beginners" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IoT for Beginners GitHub repo</a>.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="digital-swag">Digital swag<a class="hash-link" href="#digital-swag" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Check out <a href="/digitalswag">digital swag</a> page for #JulyOT social media images, sticker templates, desktop backgrounds and video chat backgrounds.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>30days</category>
            <category>iot</category>
            <category>kickoff</category>
            <category>iot4b</category>
            <category>embeddediot</category>
            <category>aiatedge</category>
            <category>iotcerts</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[00: #JulyOT Is Coming!]]></title>
            <link>https://JulyOT.dev/blog/julyot-teaser</link>
            <guid>julyot-teaser</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[#JulyOT is coming!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>#JulyOT is coming!</p></blockquote><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Jumpstart 31 days of IoT celebrations with #JulyOT" src="/assets/images/julyot-kickoff-banner-774571809d044932ac743c7c2a48c205.png" width="1000" height="420" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>We can't believe it's already the last week of June!! Wait - you know what that means right?</p><p>Clear up your cables, dust off your Raspberry Pi, dig our your Arduino board, fire up Visual Studio Code with PlatformIO, or the Arduino IDE, and login to the cloud! It's almost time to celebrate the Internet of Things, one thing at a time! It's almost #JulyOT!</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Animated JulyOT logo" src="/assets/images/julyot-single-loop-ba379e340a5963a2448fb21a1842c673.gif" width="480" height="270" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>As always #JulyOT will be kicking off on the 1st July, and every day we will be bringing you some awesome IoT content to get you excited about the Internet of Things.</p><p>We'll have a mix of live streams, videos, blog posts and code samples, all grouped into the following themes:</p><ul><li>Beginners, makers, and students</li><li>Embedded development</li><li>AI on the Edge</li><li>Learning and certifications</li></ul><p>We invite everyone to build and share your creations throughout month as you gain knowledge from these and other resources throughout #JulyOT!  Be sure to spread the word about this initiative and your own projects by sharing the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/JulyOT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">hashtag #JulyOT on social media</a>! We'll be sharing our favorite projects that we find.</p><p>Check back here daily to get all the latest goodness, or subscribe to <a href="https://julyot.dev/blog/rss.xml" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">our RSS feed</a>.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="julyot-has-a-new-home">#JulyOT has a new home!<a class="hash-link" href="#julyot-has-a-new-home" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>In the past #JulyOT has lived on the <a href="https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/internet-of-things-blog/bg-p/IoTBlog" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Microsoft IoT Tech Community</a>, but going forward we have a new home - here at <a href="https://julyOT.dev" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">JulyOT.dev</a>.</p><p>All the content for #JulyOT now lives <a href="https://github.com/JulyOT/JulyOT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">in GitHub</a>. If you want to submit content then join us there, raise an issue with what you want to add, and we can help get your content shared with the world. For blog posts you can write the whole post here, or link out to your own blog. For all other content we can link to your GitHub repo, video or wherever!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="juliot">#JulIoT<a class="hash-link" href="#juliot" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>#JulyOT is spreading it wings to Spanish! We are excited to bring you #JulIoT!</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Julio T anumated logo" src="/assets/images/juliot-811c2295bd57326df719b623d18e3252.gif" width="480" height="270" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>We have some live streams and blogs in Spanish lined up for you over the month. Check out the <a href="/livestreams">live streams</a> page for a sneak peak of whats coming!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="our-first-event">Our first event<a class="hash-link" href="#our-first-event" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Launching #JulyOT will be a series of IoT for Beginners live streams, based off the hugely popular <a href="https://aka.ms/iot-beginners" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IoT for Beginners Curriculum</a> that offers 24 free, open source lessons on IoT. We will be running the first 4 lessons as live streams, starting Friday 1st July at 9am Pacific Time.</p><a href="https://www.meetup.com/Microsoft-Reactor-Redmond/events/286453689/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.meetup.com/_next/image/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fsecure-content.meetupstatic.com%2Fimages%2Fclassic-events%2F504717110%2F676x380.webp&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75" width="45%" alt="IoT for beginners - Lesson 1, Introduction to IoT, Friday July 1st, 9am Pacific Time" class="img_ev3q"></a><p>You can register for this event on Meetup.com and get a reminder, or join us on YouTube.</p><a href="https://www.meetup.com/Microsoft-Reactor-Redmond/events/286453689" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jimbobbennett/ColoredBadges/main/svg/social/meetup.svg" alt="Meetup registration link" class="img_ev3q"></a>  <a href="https://aka.ms/IoTforbeginnersLess1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jimbobbennett/ColoredBadges/main/svg/streaming/youtube.svg" alt="YouTube live stream link" class="img_ev3q"></a><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="microsoft-cloud-skills-challenge">Microsoft Cloud Skills challenge<a class="hash-link" href="#microsoft-cloud-skills-challenge" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p><img loading="lazy" alt="A cartoon racoon holding medals" src="/assets/images/image_medals-cb4e42548a6345130e3aca09f2968f3d.svg" width="151" height="168" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>As part of #JulyOT we will be running a Microsoft Cloud Skills challenge, giving you a guided path to learn the Microsoft IoT stack, and compete in your learning against others. Check out the <a href="/skills">Cloud Skills Challenge page</a> to sign up!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="julyot-digital-swag">JulyOT digital swag<a class="hash-link" href="#julyot-digital-swag" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>This year we also have <a href="/digitalswag">#JulyOT digital swag</a>! Get a new desktop background, or a background for your favorite video chat tool like Microsoft Teams.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="iot-resources">IoT resources<a class="hash-link" href="#iot-resources" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>For more IoT resources, check out the <a href="/resources">resources link</a> above. Whether you want videos to help you learn, or beginner tutorials, we have you covered.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>30days</category>
            <category>iot</category>
            <category>kickoff</category>
            <category>iot4b</category>
            <category>embeddediot</category>
            <category>aiatedge</category>
            <category>iotcerts</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>